let's look at the solution to the first
part of our quiz the question was what
is in these registers and in these rad
entries and to answer that we need to
consider all of the things that can
happen in this cycle one of the things
that happens is we will try to issue
this instruction that might update the
rat another thing that we need to
consider is that this instruction will
broadcast its result and that might also
update the right and right to a register
we can do this in either order but we
have to figure out if they update the
same thing what happens so let's see
issuing this instruction results in
looking at the rat entries for f0 and f1
and then writing to the entry for f1 the
number of the reservation station where
we put this instruction because there is
an available reservation station this
instruction will issue there so the
entry for f1 will be changed to point to
our reservation station to the registers
are not updated when we issue an
instruction so they stay the same for
now the broadcast of the result might
update both the right and the registers
let's first see what happens to the rat
with broadcasting that our s0 is now 4.4
and that will be written two registers
so from now on we will not be using our
s0 as the name for this value that means
that this right entry will from now on
be pointing to the actual register where
we write this result and that register
is f 0 so this rat entry from now on
points to the register file because the
rat entry was pointing to RS 0 and RS 0
is broadcasting that means that the
register file actually will get value
4.4 for that register so the register
here will change and finally this
register here nobody wrote to it in this
cycle so it stays the same as it was